## Idhaya Veena

Flat # 107, 1st Floor, Rishi Ratna Apartments, Vittal Nagar, Chamrajpet, Bangalore +91 99019 99441 / email: 13082007iv@gmail.com

\_\_\_\_\_

### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

More than 2 decades of rich experience in liaising with the top management and C-level executives of various industries. A seasoned professional in the field of administration, and office management.

 Dedicated, with a positive demeanor to work under pressure. Dependable and approachable to the global business demands. Experience with senior-level executives across the globe has contributed to enhancing interpersonal and cultural skills.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Executive Support ~ Organisational and Planning Skills ~ Vendor Management ~ Business Planning ~ Attention to detail ~ Logistics Service Level Agreements ~ Team Leadership ~ Productivity Improvement ~ Organization & Communication ~ Confidentiality ~ Reliability ~ Quick Learner

### **Professional Experience**

AppViewX Pvt Ltd September 2023 till March 2024

Senior Executive Assistant to CEO (EST time zone – 5 pm to 2 am (IST)

- Providing Virtual administrative and business support to the CEO based in Florida, USA.
- Manage calendar in different time zones, scheduling series meetings, and prioritizing without any conflicts.
- Plan the Board Meetings and ensure the meetings are on the calendar for next FY, closely work with Board of Members EA's.
- Work with Investors EAs and schedule f2f or 1:1 meetings as per availabilities. Coordinate Client Meetings with the Customer Success team and schedule accordingly.
- Manage expense claims via Expense wire, Zoho.
- Book flights, and arrange hotel accommodation, and local logistics.
- Arranged for SMT Work Week offsite in Atlanta, USA. Arranged for hotel, flight bookings, airport transfers, Conference room, and customized Lunch and Dinner for all 9 SMTs.
- Arranged for team dinner in Atlanta outside the hotel for the SMT team during SMT Work Week.
- Manage calendars for two other VPs based out of the USA, (who were part of SMT), and file their expenses. Support all the VPs in scheduling meetings as per request.
- Follow up with the team for the presentations and collate the PPT, make necessary changes as required, and send it to the CEO.

#### CARGILL March 2021 till July 2023

**Executive Team Lead** 

- Providing Virtual administrative and business support to 5 directors based out of Singapore. Managed calendar in different time zones, scheduling series meetings, prioritizing without any conflicts, following up with direct reports and directors, and other stakeholders on 1:1 meetings.
- Managed expense claims (Concur, EE Web, Chrome River) and travel requisitions on behalf of the directors.

- Liaised with CWT for flight bookings, arranging hotel accommodation, and local logistics, applying for arrival passes (Thailand), and other country visas, and adhering to rules and regulations due to the pandemic. Applying for an online visa for leaders.
- On-boarding/Off-boarding for employees and contractors raising different internal ITrelated tickets to ensure employees get laptops and other accessories on joining day, working with facilities team in arranging hand phone, seating arrangement, parking, etc., for employees based out of Singapore, Philippines, Thailand, and Vietnam.
- Liaised with country HR and procurement team in arranging company leased cars for sales employees based out of Singapore, Philippines, and Vietnam.
- Registering the directors to various seminars, and working with external seminar coordinators.
- Booking meeting rooms via Outlook, and seat booking via EMS tool.
- Raise PR, PO, and invoice submission, and work closely with the finance team about payment to the vendors.
- Adding new joiners to the relevant email distribution list according to the Enterprise / BU's.
- Arranging birthday cakes, flower bouquets, gift vouchers, etc., for the Directors' team members based in different locations across the globe.
- Sending welcome communication on behalf of directors regarding new employees.
- Schedule introduction meetings for new joiners with Executive Team members and different stakeholders.
- Block table for breakfast/lunch/dinner for Directors in Singapore.
- Maintain all confidential details of the Directors in OneNote.
- Part of the Global Supervisor Leadership committee, working with different supervisors on the goals, training, backup plan, town halls, etc.,
- Connect with clients monthly, and bi-monthly, to understand their expectations from the admins, collect feedback, and address concerns.
- Team of 10 admin executive assistants reporting to me.
- Provide necessary ad-hoc support to the team members related to any process/logistics, take up the team building activities, and maintain a balanced workload for the team members.
- Maintain leave management for the entire team, this avoids conflicts in the team.
- Assign the leaders to the admins based on Enterprise/workload distribution
- Assign on-boarding/off-boarding to the admin based on Enterprise/BU's
- Have a continuous conversation with the team members every week, get brief updates on their support to the clients, address pain points, where they require my support, and provide feedback on areas of improvement based on the feedback received from clients, prepare MOM's and document on teams' folder.
- Set goals for the admin team, and coach them on the development
- Liaise with different stakeholders and arrange refresher training on the process.
- Work with the HR team in recruiting new members to the team.
- Work with IT, facility in getting the laptops, arrange onboarding training with different stakeholders, and arrange KT from the team members to the new joiners.
- Allocate clients to the admins, and introduce admin to the clients by sending introduction email.
- Present trivia/activity slides using Mentimeter during Team meetings, Town halls, etc.,
- Create and circulate mid-year/year-end performance survey forms to the clients.
- Schedule mid-year and year-end performance reviews for the admin team, sign off on their compensation, variable pay, etc.,
- Work on a backup plan for the admin team.

### NXP India Pvt Ltd February 2014 to March 2021

EA to Bangalore Site Head, BU Directors, India HR Director, India CFO, and other Project Directors and support the team of 300 +

- Provide administrative and business support to the Site Head & other directors, arrange travel, limousine services, and luxury hotel reservations, provide a travel folder to the Site Head and the Directors with a detailed agenda, and all travel arrangements reconfirmed before travel day.
- Manage calendar different time zones, scheduling series meetings, prioritizing without any conflicts, following up with Global and India stakeholders on 1:1 meeting
- Coordinate the seminars, and work with the external organizers.
- Enhanced communication between Directors and executive team, fostering a sense of teamwork and collaboration.
- Organising and maintaining "bring forward systems" to ensure documentation is available for forthcoming meetings
- Prepare confidential reports, organization charts, and tables regarding operations & productivity
- Regularly meet with other EAs on their support to the BU's and guide them.
- Coordinate the yearly events, organising the posters, and giveaways for external speakers, arranging end-to-end logistics for the external speakers.
- Coordinate with the Global Team in getting the slides, arrange VC, teleconference, live meeting, Town halls via webinar, Teams.
- Arrange end-to-end logistics for visitors traveling from Global, preparing agendas, scheduling meetings, scheduling interviews, etc.
- Arrange meetings, training, events finding a location, catering, attending the events to provide support, prepare materials and other needs for a successful event
- Arrange Management offsite, project team offsite, team lunch, dinner, get together
- Manage concur claims for expense and travel requisition and approve on behalf of the directors
- On-boarding, Off-boarding, Extension for employees/contractors/interns, and raising different internal IT-related tickets to ensure employees get relevant access to the system.
- Adding new joiners to the relevant email distribution list according to the projects.
- Maintained floor-wise seating mapping Excel file.
- Worked with the IT team in creating an Intranet page for the Bangalore site with required details about Company, Product, ET Members, etc.,

#### CGI, Bangalore 2007 to 2013

Executive Secretary cum Sr. Executive PMO - Managing Director/ Director - Application Management /CPO

- Provide administrative and business support to CPO and other management executives, manage calendar in different time zones, schedule meetings, arrange travel, limousine services, and luxury hotel reservations, provide travel folder to CPO and the executives with detailed itinerary, all travel arrangements reconfirmed before travel day.
- Review incoming emails, sorting them into the agreed categories (delete/ignore/file/respond on behalf/put up with prioritization), handling the emails that should not need CPO attention.
- Prepare and review reports, spreadsheets, presentations, and finished documents relative to CPO's assignment. Prepare confidential reports, organization charts, and tables regarding operations & productivity

• Tracked login-in and log-out time of all the employees, this was required to plan a hot desk seating facility in the office premises.

### SunTechnics Energy Systems Pvt Ltd Bangalore, 2006 to 2007

Executive Secretary to MD (Expat) cum Sales Coordinator

- Handled confidential portfolio, organized travel routines, and hotel accommodation
- Arranged Management Meetings in India & overseas, traveled to Singapore along with the Management Executives.
- Arranged complete logistics for the team traveling from other parts of the globe, arranged site visits, and accompanied them
- Preparation of proposals, assisting the sales & marketing team and keeping track of proposals as this was useful for the country manager for the monthly forecast.

# Trident Infosol Pvt Ltd Bangalore, 2004 to 2006

Executive Assistant to VP cum Office Coordinator

- Handled calendar, arranging meetings, travel routines, hotel accommodation
- Preparing Proposals, working closely with the sales team in following up on the PO and payments
- Handled stock department, took the count on incoming, outgoing, and internal stocks, worked with one of the engineers, and created software to maintain a stock inventory of ICs, rugged boards, Monitor, etc.,
- Assisting HR manager in HR-related activities, scheduling interviews, maintenance of database applications and confidential files

#### Basant Betons Bangalore, 2000 to 2004

**Executive Secretary CEO** 

- Handled calendar, arranging meetings, travel routines, hotel accommodation
- Administration and vendor development of housekeeping, pantry, and stationery
- Handled Salary for the entire office and factory staff as the salary advisor was on long medical leave.
- Worked on import and export invoices, interacting with concerned customs to export Granite. We were importing machinery for our factory.

### **Gujarat Glass Ltd** Bangalore, 1998 to 2000

Secretary to RM cum Administrator

- Coordinated with other service functional heads for the smooth functioning of the departments.
- Target Planning, Objective setting, and realization of targets

#### Ramanashree Comforts Hotel Bangalore, 1997 to 1998

Secretary to EM cum Front Office Executive

• Handled check-in, check-out, different modes of payment, EPABX, etc.

# **EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT**

•	Schooling	St. Teresa's High School	Bangalore
•	BA (Distance Education)	Madurai Kamaraj University	Bangalore
•	Diploma in Secretarial Practice	The Career College	Bangalore